

14164 NW Greenwood Dr, Portland OR, 97229 eddiew@stanford.edu Home: (503) 439-1431

eddiew.net

#### PROFILE

I am a budding software developer with 5 years of programming experience and 3 months of professional experience seeking a summer internship in software development. I look forward to being a team player and building new professional relationships.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Intel DCSG - Software Development Intern (June-September, 2013)

Developed a project management web application for the Scrum agile methodology using ASP.NET MVC. Wrote queries to Rational Team Concert, ClearQuest, and other internal databases in C# to track story points and defects, and created Metro-UI styled JavaScript applets to display defect history, sprint burndown/burnup, and team velocity. Followed Scrum methodologies and collaborated with developers based in Poland.

### Front-End Web Development (2013-present)

Created personal websites with responsive layouts and graceful degradation. Wrote Ruby scripts for deploy-time optimizations including source file preprocessing, concatenation, minification, and compression. Used JavaScript, JQuery, and Bootstrap to create plugins and UI elements.

### Android App Development (2012-present)

Developed Android apps using Eclipse and IntelliJ. Projects involved the use of the Android Native Development Kit, OpenGL ES 3.0, and 3<sup>rd</sup> party APIs.

### FIRST Robotics Team - Team Captain (2009-present)

Oversaw the development of 10,000+ lines of C by 6 high school students, among other tasks, and led team to world championship finals 3 years in a row. Employed scrum methodologies and used Git for version control.

TECHNICAL	
SUMMARY	,

Languages:	Java, C++, C, JavaScript, C#, Ruby, Python
Concepts:	OOP, Agile Methodologies (Scrum), OpenGL, ASP.NET MVC
Software:	Git, Rational Team Concert, ClearQuest, Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Cygwin
Systems:	Windows, Android, Linux, Arduino

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Stanford University** (to graduate in 2018)

Pursuing Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

# Portland Community College (2012-2013)

Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Digital Logic

#### OTHER

#### **Boy Scouts of America Eagle Scout**

**Founder of Spark Technology Education**, an Oregon 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization dedicated to providing extracurricular STEM experiences to K-12 students.